Professional summary

IT professional with 24 years of experience. Skills in Network Attached Storage (NAS) and Storage Area Networks (SAN) with a focus on NetApp Storage (ONTAP, CIFS, NFS, FC, Data Replication, Data Migration). Strong work ethic with a drive to learn.

Employment

Capgemini | Storage Administrator | Remote

Dec 2013 - June 2024

Ensured optimal performance and reliability of Honeywell's storage environment. Diagnosed and resolved outages, administered CIFS/NFS/FCP, and configured new storage devices. Upgraded software and microcode, managed storage allocations and reclaims, and performed data replication and migrations. Worked with NetApp, Hitachi, VAST Data, HPE Nimble, EMC storage devices, and Cisco switches.

IBM | Held Several Positions | Boulder, CO (2000 to 2013)

Storage Administrator

May 2011 - Dec 2013

Resolved critical storage issues for multiple accounts, ensuring system reliability and uptime. Managed storage allocations, reclaims, and hardware replacements, enhancing operational efficiency. Collaborated with teams using NetApp and IBM FAStT storage, and Cisco switches, improving workflow integration. Conducted general maintenance of storage environment, preventing potential disruptions. Performed problem determination and recovery, boosting client satisfaction.

Business Recovery Manager

Nov 2005 - May 2011

Drove recovery efforts for IBM eBusiness, ACI Worldwide, Whirlpool, and Wellpoint accounts, maintaining operational continuity. Assessed impact and coordinated recovery actions for business-critical outages, ensuring swift resolution. Acted as focal point for escalations, significantly reducing downtime and improving service reliability. Conducted management notifications, ensuring clear communication and timely updates during outages.

OnDemand Data Center Transition Leader

Nov 2004 - Nov 2005

Collaborated with project managers to transition new accounts into OnDemand Data Center Operations. Developed and organized account-specific documentation, ensuring seamless transitions. Tested monitoring tools and trained operations staff, enhancing team efficiency. Streamlined processes, resulting in measurable improvements in data center operations.

Situational Duty Manager

Aug 2002 - Nov 2004

Drove critical situation outages for multiple accounts. Acted as a point of escalation. Conducted management notifications and coordinated recovery actions.

Mark Raudenbush

markraud@hotmail.com • (303) 725-2585

Distributed Operations Team Leader

Jan 2002 - Aug 2002

Lead team in monitoring IBM internal servers and infrastructure. Worked closely with support and management to improve monitoring and establish/maintain processes and procedures.

Operations Transition Team Leader

June 2001 - Jan 2002

Franklin Templeton Operations Center Transition: Collaborated with various teams to document processes and procedures during the transition of Franklin Templeton's operations center from Florida to Boulder. Prepared the operations center in Boulder, ensuring connectivity, hardware, and software were in place.

Disaster Recovery and Fiduciary Trust Transition: Assisted in disaster recovery efforts following 9/11. Facilitated the transition of Fiduciary Trust from New Jersey to Boulder. Worked with different teams to establish processes and procedures for the new operations center in Boulder.

Systems Management Professional, Operations

June 2000 - June 2001

Monitored IBM's internal servers using Tivoli. Collaborated closely with support and management to address critical hardware and software issues.

Skills

- NetApp Storage (CIFS, NFS, FC)
- Hitachi Storage (FC)
- Cisco SAN Administration (DCNM)
- HPE Nimble Storage

- EMC VNX Storage
- VAST Data Storage (NFS)
- Programming: Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Education

University of Denver | Denver, CO

Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

Full Stack Coding Boot Camp (web development)

New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM

Aug 1995 - Dec 1999

Bachelor of Business Administrations - Business Computer Systems

Certifications

- Coursera Python for Everybody Specialization
- LPI Linux Essentials
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals

Links

www.linkedin.com/in/markraudenbush

www.github.com/markraud